Guide to the Benjamin Severance Winchester Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Subject Files, Series III
  - Religious education
    - Curriculum: Typical and Life Situations to instruct young people in proper morals for the Federal Council of Churches of America's Council of Correlation of Programs for Religious Education (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Curriculum: Typical and Life Situations to instruct young people in proper morals for the Federal Council of Churches of America's Council of Correlation of Programs for Religious Education (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Curriculum: Teaching Units for the Federal Council of Churches of America's Council of Correlation of Programs for Religious Education (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Fairfield County (Connecticut) Council of Churches and Religious Education: reports, correspondence, and programs, 1933-1934, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: bulletins, curriculum, International Council of Religious Education meeting minutes, 1933, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: curriculum, International Council of Religious Education meeting minutes, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: curriculum, International Council of Religious Education meeting minutes, Winchester's notes, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: curriculum, discussion questions, Federal Council of Churches meeting minutes, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: curriculum and reports pertaining to child growth and sex education (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: curriculum sex education and family life generally (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: curriculum sex education and discussion questions for family religious education (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education: National Council of Parent Education conference discussion guide, Parent-Teacher Association meeting outline and report, newsletters and pamphlets on the subject, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Family and Parent Religious Education correspondence, 1915-1917, 1924, 1928, 1932-1936 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Christian Education: meeting minutes and reports, 1917, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Christian Education: meeting minutes and reports, 1916-1918, 1926-1927 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Christian Education: correspondence, 1917 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Christian Education: correspondence, 1917, 1928-1929, 1933-1936 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission's Council of Correlation of Religious Education: meeting minutes and notes, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission's Council of Correlation of Religious Education: meeting minutes and notes, 1924-1925 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Inter-Church Federations: correspondence, 1917 Aug (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Inter-Church Federations: correspondence; Federal Council of Churches Commission on Religious Education: reports, 1917 Sep-Oct (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Religious Education: correspondence, 1915 Jan- 1916 Oct (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Religious Education: correspondence, 1916 Nov-1917 May (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Religious Education: correspondence, 1917 June-Oct (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Religious Education: correspondence, 1917 Nov-1918 May, 1922 Oct-1923 Feb (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission on Religious Education: correspondence, 1923 Oct-1926 Oct (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Home Missions Board of the Congregational and Christian Churches: colleges funded and packets on other activities such as churches in rural America and assisting immigrant children, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Inter-Faith Cooperation, International Sunday School Lesson Committee statements, International Council of Religious Education's Curriculum Guide, 1924, 1930, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - International Council of Religious Education: reports, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - International Council of Religious Education: reports, including those on Improved Uniform Lessons, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - International Council of Religious Education: reports and curriculum, 1928-1929 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - International Council of Religious Education: reports and meeting notes concerning a merger with the Federal Council of Churches Commission on Christian Education, 1926, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - International Council of Religious Education: reports and meeting notes, 1924-1927 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - International Council of Religious Education: reports and meeting notes, 1922-1925, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - International Council of Religious Education: curriculum and meeting notes concerning young people's leadership education, 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - International Council of Religious Education: curriculum for young people's leadership education, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - International Council of Religious Education: Leadership Education correspondence, 1917, 1932-1934, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Marriage Education: correspondence, 1929-1930 May (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Marriage Education: correspondence, 1930 May-1931, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum and minute meetings, 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum and pamphlets, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 2-3)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum and minute meetings, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum, leaflets, and meeting minutes, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum, printed articles, and meeting minutes, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum and a paper read at Church Congress, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum and pamphlets, 1925, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
    - Marriage Education by the Federal Council of Churches: curriculum and meeting minutes, 1929-1930 (Box 11, Folder 10, 9)
    - Marriage Education by the International Council of Religious Education: curriculum, notes, meeting outlines, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 11, 9)
    - Marriage Education by the International Council of Religious Education: curriculum, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 10, 12)
    - Miscellaneous: meeting reports, 1912, 1916-18 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous: pamphlets, articles, notes, correspondence, 1918, 1924, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1926-1937 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous: lecture notes and reports (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Missionary Education Movement of the U.S. and Canada:correspondence reports, notes on curricula-making, 1916-1918, 1925, 1927, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Near East Relief: leaflets, religious education curriculum materials for children, 1925-1926 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Near East Relief: religious education curriculum materials for children, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Public Schools: court cases from New York relating to religious education in public schools, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Public Schools: court cases from New York relating to religious education in public schools, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Public Schools: court cases from New York relating to religious education in public schools and written interpretations of the rulings, 1927, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Public Schools: reports, articles, pamphlets relating to religious education in public schools, 1927, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Public Schools: statements, papers, and correspondence relating to religious education in public schools, 1915--1917, 1923, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Sunday Schools: correspondence, 1915-1918 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Sunday Schools: committee reports concerning curriculum from the World's Sunday School Association and the Connecticut Sunday School Association, 1915, 1918 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Sunday Schools: New York State Sunday School Association budget proposals, reports, meeting minutes, 1926-1928 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Sunday Schools: New York State Sunday School Association budget proposals, reports, meeting minutes, 1926-1927 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Sunday School Council of Evangelical Denominations - Minutes, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Surveys of Christian and economic knowledge, 1922, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Teacher Training for religious education instruction: correspondence, 1915 Sept-1916 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Teacher Training for religious education instruction: correspondence, 1917-1918, 1924, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Teacher Training for religious education instruction: curriculum, pamphlets, articles, 1928-1929 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Teacher Training for religious education instruction: curriculum, pamphlets, articles, 1916, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Vacation Religious Schools: correspondence, curriculum, 1916-1918, 1924, 1926-1927, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Vacation Religious Schools: curriculum, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Weekday Religious Education: correspondence and curriculum, 1916-1918 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Weekday Religious Education: meeting notes and plans for implementation, 1917, 1926, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      General note
      Contains information from the Greater New York Federation of Churches and the New York State Sunday School Association. Dr. Winchester served on the Education Committee of the New York Sunday School Association starting in 1926.
    - Weekday Religious Education: curriculum and pamphlets supporting implementation, 1921, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Weekday Religious Education in Georgetown, CT: announcements, bulletins, and curriculum, 1935-1937 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Work and Religious Education: curriculum, 1933-1935 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Young Children's Religious Education: correspondence and curriculum, 1916, 1924, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Young Children's Religious Education: curriculum (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Young People's Religious Education: correspondence, 1915-1918 April (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Young People's Religious Education: correspondence, 1924 Feb-May (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Young People's Religious Education: correspondence, 1924 June-Nov (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Young People's Religious Education: correspondence, 1924 Dec-1925-1927, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Young People's Religious Education: curriculum (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Young People's Religious Education: curriculum, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Young People's Religious Education: curriculum, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Young Adult Religious Education: curriculum and research material (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous
    - American Social Hygiene Association: leaflets relating to recreation, sex education, 1922, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Boy Scouts: leaflets, bulletins, committee information, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Church and Community: efforts to promote community programs including pamphlets, newsletters, and reports, 1933, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Connecticut Conference Congregational and Christian Churches: programs and correspondence, 1916, 1934-1935, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Federal Council of Churches Administrative Committee: meeting minutes, 1917-1918 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Federal Council of Churches Commission of Evangelism: meeting minutes, memos, 1925, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Federal Council of Churches Board of Finance: meeting minutes, 1925, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Federal Council of Churches Committee of Secretaries: meeting minutes, 1926, 1929-1931 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Federal Council of Churches: various subcommittee reports and minute minutes, 1924-1925, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Federal Council of Churches Committee of Worship: minutes, notes, correspondence, 1916-1918, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Financial Education: newsletters and curriculum, 1933, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Gilbert Memorial Church: various information on deacons, songs, programs of service, 1934-1935, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Gilbert Memorial Church and Winnetka Congregational Church: Order of Worship, pamphlets, membership statistics, budget information, etc., 1903, 1934-1936, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Gilbert Memorial Church located in Georgetown, Connecticut. Winnetka Congregational Church located in Winnetka, Illinois.
    - Gilbert Memorial Church: correspondence, 1934-1936, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Hymn Society of America: meeting minutes, festival programs and leaflets, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Hymn Society of America: leaflets, conference papers, reports, 1934-1936 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Hymn Society of America: meeting minutes, bulletins, festival program and leaflets, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Hymn Society of America: hymn authors information, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Hymn Society of America: correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Inter-Church Cooperation: meeting notes and plans, 1917-1918 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - John Milton Foundation: meeting minutes, reports, and membership lists, 1927-1928 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - John Milton Foundation: meeting minutes, reports, and correspondence, 1929, 1933-1937 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Life Extension Institute, 1923-1927 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Methodist Episcopal Church (MEC) and MEC, South: reports on religious education, missionary education, and leadership education, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Morality in Movies: reports and correspondence, including some by the Motion Picture Research Council, 1927, 1933-1935 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Morality in Movies: reports and correspondence by the Motion Picture Research Council, 1933-1935 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - National Safety Council: correspondence, reports, and leaflets., 1924-1925, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Obscene Literature Prevention Campaign: brochures, pamphlets, and correspondence, 1914, 1926-1927 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Radio: pamphlets, leaflets, and many "Education by Radio" bulletins, 1933-1935, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, including "A Primer for Consumers" by Benson Y. Landis, "Pathways to Nature Appreciation", "New Relationships with Jews and Catholics", "Religious Liberty - Civilization's Barometer", 1928-1937 (Box 17, Folder 6)